#### Contact

ahmed.samy18296@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ahmed-samy-datascientist (LinkedIn) github.com/Ahmedsamy96 (Personal) call.whatsapp.com/voice/YQi41ImL8aBkqxf4YYwzaF (Personal)

## Top Skills

Netezza

DataStage

**Azure Databricks** 

## Languages

Arabic (Native or Bilingual)
English (Professional Working)
French (Elementary)

### Certifications

Introduction to Programming Using Python

SQL Fundamentals

Statistics Fundamentals with Python

Python Fundamentals

Intro to Machine Learning

#### Honors-Awards

IT internship

IT internship

# **Ahmed Samy**

Sr. Data Scientist @ e& UAE | Al Master's Student | Data Science instructor @ NTI

Cairo, Egypt

## Summary

Data Scientist with 4 years' experience in building data-intensive applications overcoming complex architectural, and scalability issues in diverse industries. Proficient in predictive modeling, data processing, and data mining algorithms, as well as programming and scripting languages, including python and java. Capable of Creating, testing, and deploying highly adaptive diverse services to translate business and functional qualifications into sustainable deliverables.

# Experience

e& UAE

Senior Solutions Architect February 2024 - Present (4 months)

**United Arab Emirates** 

As a Senior Solutions Architect at e& UAE, I specialize in leveraging AI, data science, and statistical methodologies to develop tailored solutions within the telecommunication market specially in the B2C section products.

Key Responsibilities:

Solution Development: Building customized solutions utilizing algorithms, machine learning techniques, and generative AI to address the diverse needs of clientele across various industries.

Integration Expertise: Crafting integrated solutions that seamlessly deliver results to production services, ensuring an effective impact on customer service experiences and service quality standards.

e& global services Senior Data Scientist February 2024 - Present (4 months) Cairo, Egypt National Telecommunication Institute (NTI)
Data science Instructor
March 2023 - Present (1 year 3 months)
Egypt

Create and deliver the course to teach post-graduate students to understand data flow in machine learning and data science projects, including all steps and stages in data science and implement various projects as an application to the content.

Austin Artificial Intelligence, Inc.
Data Scientist
October 2023 - February 2024 (5 months)
Lakeway, TX

Orbits IT
Artificial Intelligence Engineer
May 2023 - October 2023 (6 months)
Cairo, Egypt

Working on an AI project mainly computer Vision for a governmental organization in Saudi Arabia to enhance the quality of the road using our generative AI and Computer Vision skills.

The project includes model deployment on edge devices [ Cameras Fixed on cars, Drones, and mobile application ], all related to an SQL server DB to Save the detections and tracks, which requires high skills in MLOPS and deployment experience.

Fixed Solutions
Data Scientist
January 2022 - May 2023 (1 year 5 months)
Cairo, Egypt

Worked on data generated from big scale of digital transformation projects for the Egyptian ministries digitizing program.

These projects required high analytical skills, data pipelining skills, and workflows planning which gave me a very critical and important skills and experience as a Data Scientist.

Many open source and non open source technologies and tools are used in our tasks such as Apache spark - Delta lake - Tableau - Apache Airflow - Time

Series Analysis - Text similarity models - Advanced pandas - Postgres DB - and other many tools to increase the data flow efficiency and prepare the data in best shape to be used for giving insights and being ready for business intelligence Analytics and ML predictions and forecasting.

The Sparks Foundation
Data Scientist
April 2022 - June 2022 (3 months)

Omdena Giza Chapter Data Science CONTRIBUTE February 2022 - March 2022 (2 months) Cairo, Egypt

Information Technology Institute (ITI)
AI & ML Trainee
April 2021 - December 2021 (9 months)
New Cairo, Cairo, Egypt

It was a 9 Months post-grade studying Artificial intelligence and Machine Learning with Information technology institute (ITI) with partnership with EPITA.

Self employed 4 years 10 months Junior Web Developer November 2017 - September 2019 (1 year 11 months) Egypt

Network Engineer
December 2014 - August 2018 (3 years 9 months)
Egypt

#### **IBM**

business intelligence analytics February 2018 - February 2018 (1 month)

Dell EMC cloud infrastructure & services August 2017 - December 2017 (5 months)

**EGYPTAIR** 

## Trainee

January 2017 - February 2017 (2 months)

مطار القاهرة

Ministry of Communications and Information Technology (MCIT),

Egypt

Trainee

July 2016 - August 2016 (2 months)

smart village

just trainee.

## Education

Zagazig University

Bachelor's degree, Computer and Information Sciences and Support Services · (2014 - 2018)

Information Technology Institute (ITI)

Post-grad , Artificial Intelligence · (April 2021 - December 2021)

Zagazig University

Master's degree, Artificial Intelligence and Information Systems · (October 2022 - October 2024)